Draper Corporation Glass Plate Negatives 6612 GPN
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series A: 5 x 7 inch negatives.
  - Prospect Heights, units 7-14, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905 (Box 22, Folder 336)
    Negative no.A336. September 6, 1905. Image depicts a view of units 7 through 14 at Prospect Heights in Milford, Massachusetts The units are connected townhouse style, with eight separate entrances (two are double, the others are single), and are made out of brick. The entire building is two stories with a small window visible in the third story on each end. There are chimneys on each end, in the middle, and two in the rear. Another set of connected townhouses can be glimpsed on the right. Grass plots line the front, separated by walkways to each entrance. A large grassy area is in the foreground. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. See Box 11, Negative 119 for what appears to be another view of these same units, and Box 23, Negative 346 for what appears to be an almost identical view taken September 29, 1905. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 1, Item 336 for print of this negative.
  - Housing in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905 (Box 22, Folder 339)
    Negative no.A339. September 6, 1905. Image depicts a group of two-story brick buildings designed to accommodate two or more families. The buildings' features include multiple chimneys, shutters at each window, and lawns. An open field is in the foreground. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. See Box 23, Negative 347 for an almost identical view taken September 29, 1905, and Box 131, Negative 99 for a broader view than seen here. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 1, Item 339 for print of this negative.
  - Close-up view of housing in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905 (Box 22, Folder 340)
    Negative no.A340. September 6, 1905. Image depicts a closer view of a line of townhouses in Prospect Heights, two-story brick buildings designed to accommodate two or more families. These buildings feature Tudor-style timbering in the gables, roofed entrances (some single, some double), and shutters at all the windows (some closed). Based on the entrances this set of townhouses probably contained eight apartments. There are small lawns in front between the houses and the street. Open space is in the foreground. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. These houses can also be seen at the beginning of a stretch of homes in Box 136, Negative 190. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 1, Item 340 for print of this negative.
  - Bancroft Memorial Library, 1905 (Box 23, Folder 341)
    Negative no.A341. September 6, 1905. Image depicts a single-story stone building with an arched doorway, situated on a street corner. It is partially hidden by trees. The library was donated to the town in 1898 by Joseph Bancroft, a Draper Company executive, in memory of his wife, Sylvia. The building was designed by Boston architect C. Howard Walker. It is constructed of Milford granite, and was modeled after Merton College Chapel at Oxford. On the left are marble sculptures that include an eagle, Greek goddess, two urns, and a bench. See Negative 352, in this box, for a clearer view of the library and sculptures. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 341 for print of this negative.
  - Bancroft Memorial Library, 1905 (Box 23, Folder 342)
    Negative no.A342. September 6, 1905. Image depicts a single-story stone building with an arched doorway, situated on a street corner. It is partially hidden by trees. The library was donated to the town in 1898 by Joseph Bancroft, a Draper Company executive, in memory of his wife, Sylvia. The building was designed by Boston architect C. Howard Walker. It is constructed of Milford granite, and was modeled after Merton College Chapel at Oxford. On the left are marble sculptures that include an eagle, Greek goddess, two urns, and a bench. See Negative 352, in this box, for a clearer view of the library and sculptures. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 342 for print of this negative.
  - Hopedale House, 1905 (Box 23, Folder 343)
    Negative no.A343. September 8, 1905. Image depicts a four-story wooden boarding house surrounded by other single- and multiple-story residences. The building has one large and two smaller chimneys and a lightning rod. Shutters are installed at all windows. A front porch runs the length of the building and a climbing vine provides shade. A sign "Hopedale House" can be seen above the porch roof. A fire escape is visible on the left-hand end of the building. Trees are planted between buildings and in the background view. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer Draper were responsible for creating the integrated, planned community of Hopedale with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces, in addition to employment. See Box 15, Negative 186 and Box 22, Negative 334 for much closer views of Hopedale House and Negative 344, in this box, for the same view seen here but from more of a distance. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 343 for print of this negative.
  - Hopedale House, 1905 (Box 23, Folder 344)
    Negative no.A344. September 8, 1905. Image depicts a four-story wooden boarding house surrounded by other single- and multiple-story residences. The building has one large and two smaller chimneys and a lightning rod. Shutters are installed at all windows. A front porch runs the length of the building and a climbing vine provides shade. A sign "Hopedale House" is barely visible above the porch roof. A fire escape is visible on the left-hand end of the building. Trees are planted between buildings and in the background view. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer Draper were responsible for creating the integrated, planned community of Hopedale with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces, in addition to employment. See Box 15, Negative 186 for a much closer view of Hopedale House and Negative 343, in this box, for the same image seen here but from less of a distance. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 344 for print of this negative.
  - House in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905 (Box 23, Folder 345)
    Negative no.A345. September 29, 1905. Image depicts a two-story brick building designed as a two-family residence. The building has four chimneys and two entrances in the front. A lawn, clothesline (on the left), and field are in the foreground. Other residences are in the background. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by the firm of Peabody & Stearns. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 345 for print of this negative.
  - Prospect Heights, units 7-14, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905 (Box 23, Folder 346)
    Negative no.A346. September 29, 1905. Image depicts a view of units 7 through 14 at Prospect Heights in Milford, Massachusetts The units are connected townhouse style, with eight separate entrances (two are double, the others are single), and are made out of brick. The entire building is two stories with a small window visible in the third story on each end. There are chimneys on each end, in the middle, and two in the rear. Grass plots line the front, separated by walkways to each entrance. A large grassy area is in the foreground. Other housing (without the gambrel roofs) are to the right. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. See Box 11, Negative 119 for what appears to be another view of these same units, and Box 22, Negative 336 for what appears to be an almost identical view taken September 6, 1905. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 346 for print of this negative.
  - Housing in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905 (Box 23, Folder 347)
    Negative no.A347. September 29, 1905. Image depicts a group of two-story brick buildings designed to accommodate two or more families. The buildings' features include multiple chimneys, shutters at each window, and lawns. An open field is in the foreground. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. See Box 22, Negative 339 for an almost identical view taken September 6, 1905, and Box 131, Negative 99 for a broader view than seen here. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 347 for print of this negative.
  - Housing in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905 (Box 23, Folder 348)
    Negative no.A348. September 29, 1905. Image depicts a group of two-story brick buildings designed to accommodate two or more families. The buildings' features include multiple chimneys, shutters at each window, and lawns. An open field is in the foreground. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. See Box 22, Negative 339 for an almost identical view taken September 6, 1905, and Box 131, Negative 99 for a broader view than seen here. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 348 for print of this negative.
  - Houses in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905 (Box 23, Folder 349)
    Negative no.A349. September 29, 1905. Image depicts a two- story brick building designed to accommodate multiple families. The building is the end unit of what is probably a string of attached townhouses. A street lamp and stone wall are in view along the street. Building features include chimneys and shutters at each window, and some Tudor-style timbers decorating the gable. The building has a small lawn that reaches to the sidewalk in front. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 349 for print of this negative.
  - Two houses in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts, 1905 (Box 23, Folder 350)
    Negative no.A350. September 29, 1905. Image depicts two two-story brick buildings designed to accommodate two or more families. Building features include chimneys and shutters at each window. Each residence has a small lawn that reaches to the sidewalk in front. A grassy field is in the foreground view. The house on the left is a two-family; the house on the right appears to be a multiple- family. Glimpses of similar housing can be seen behind these units. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 350 for print of this negative.
  - Town Hall, 1906 (Box 23, Folder 351)
    Negative no.A351. May 31, 1906. Image depicts a three-story stone building situated on a street corner. The building was designed by architect Fred Swasey of Milford and built in 1886; it appears to be in the Romanesque style, somewhat similar to that of H. H. Richardson. The building has two chimneys and a gabled roof with decorative ironwork running along the upper edge. There are three entrances at the front; two women and one man pose in front of the entrance between windows that read "Post Office." Another man leans against the building in one of the other entrances. A horse-drawn cart or wagon is partially in view on the street on the left; "Hopedale" is printed on the top edge of the cart. See also Box 134, Negative 160. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 351 for print of this negative.
  - Bancroft Memorial Library, 1906 (Box 23, Folder 352)
    Negative no.A352. June 6, 1906. Image depicts a single-story stone building with an arched doorway and windows. The library was donated to the town in 1898 by Joseph Bancroft, a Draper Company executive, in memory of his wife, Sylvia. The building was designed by Boston architect C. Howard Walker. It is constructed of Milford granite, and was modeled after Merton College Chapel at Oxford. On the left are marble sculptures that include an eagle, Greek goddess, two urns, and a bench; part of this group contains a fountain. See Box 21, Negative 317 for a view of the fountain; see Box 130, Negative 77 and Negative 78, and Negative 342, in this box, for other views of the library. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 352 for print of this negative.
  - Tube Race, Field Day, 1906 (Box 23, Folder 355)
    Negative no.A355. August 18, 1906. Image depicts a bath house and residential buildings in the distance, viewed from across Hopedale Pond. Two men are in sitting in inner tubes in the water, but most people (including some women) appear to be in canoes. The heads of a few spectators are in the immediate foreground; other spectators can be seen on the dock outside the bath house. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 355 for print of this negative.
  - Boat Race, Field Day, 1906 (Box 23, Folder 356)
    Negative no.A356. August 18, 1906. Image depicts the start of the boat race at Field Day, with six rowboats, each with two male rowers, lined up to begin the race. Spectators are seated in boats along the shore in foreground and are also seen at the bath house on the opposite shore of Hopedale Pond. Note the two women with parasols in the boat on the right. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 356 for print of this negative.
  - High Jump, Field Day, 1906 (Box 23, Folder 357)
    Negative no.A357. August 18, 1906. Image depicts a man jumping over a pole (perhaps four feet high) that spans two side supports. He wears a shirt with the letter B in front. Officials stand by observing his jump. Spectators (mostly men) line both sides of the field. See Box 24, Negative 362, Negative 378, and Negative 379 for other views of the high jump. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 357 for print of this negative.
  - Obstacle Race, Field Day, 1906 (Box 23, Folder 358)
    Negative no.A358. August 18, 1906. Image depicts men crawling into tubes of fabric that lay on the ground. Once at the far end, they need to stand up, fully enveloped in the tube, and make their way to the next obstacle or to a finish line. One man is fully enveloped and partially upright; two are in the middle of crawling through the tubes; one is just entering a tube. Officials and spectators (men and women) look on. See also Negative 360, in this box, and Box 24, Negative 376 and Negative 377. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 358 for print of this negative.
  - Cricket Match, Field Day, 1906 (Box 23, Folder 359)
    Negative no.A359. August 18, 1906. Image depicts men playing their field positions and a batter in place. A few spectators look on from beneath trees on the sideline on the right, barely visible. The field is large and well maintained. Residential houses are visible In the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer Draper were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 359 for print of this negative.
  - Another Obstacle Race challenge, Field Day, 1906 (Box 23, Folder 360)
    Negative no.A360. Another Obstacle Race challenge, Field Day, Hopedale, Massachusetts Gelatin silver print, [1974], from a glass plate negative, August 18, 1906. Image depicts another part of the obstacle race: men climbing through wooden barrels and then across a series of ropes hanging above the ground from a wooden frame. Officials and spectators look on. See also Negative 358, in this box, and Box 242, Negative 376 and Negative 377. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 360 for print of this negative.
  - High Kick, Field Day, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 361)
    Negative no.A361. High Kick, Field Day, Hopedale, Massachusetts Gelatin silver print, [1974], from a glass plate negative, August 18, 1906. Image depicts a man in mid-air kicking right leg upward to hit an object hanging from a wooden frame. Officials and spectators look on. See Negative 374, in this box, for an almost identical view. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 361 for print of this negative.
  - High Jump, Field Day, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 362)
    Negative no.A362. August 18, 1906. Image depicts a man attempting to jump over a pole (about 4.5 feet high) that spans two side supports. Officials stand by observing his jump. Spectators line both sides of the field. See Box 23, Negative 357, and Negative 378 and Negative 379, in this folder, for other views of the high jump. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 362 for print of this negative.
  - Pole Vault, Field Day, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 363)
    Negative no.A363. August 18, 1906. Image depicts a man participating in the pole vault. Having first propelled himself into the air with the use of a pole, he is pictured just clearing a horizontal bar held up by two supports. Officials stand by observing his vault. Spectators line both sides of the field; a tent is visible in the right background. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 363 for print of this negative.
  - Girls' Potato Race, Field Day, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 364)
    Negative no.A364. August 18, 1906. Image depicts three girls, each carrying a potato (possibly on a spoon?) and racing to their container (in the foreground) to place their potato without dropping it. Officials stand by observing the race. Spectators line both sides of the field; a number of girls in the background are probably about to participate, or already have participated, in the race. This event was most likely organized by the Draper Company and may have consisted entirely of Draper Company employees, or in this case, children of employees. See also Negative 375, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 364 for print of this negative.
  - Boating, Field Day, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 365)
    Negative no.A365. August 18, 1906. Image depicts the bath house and residential buildings on the opposite shore of Hopedale Pond. It is unclear if anything organized is ongoing, but several groups of people are enjoying rowing boats and canoes on the water, along with one man in an inner tube. Note the two women in the boat in the foreground, one holding a parasol. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 365 for print of this negative.
  - Canoe Tug-of-War, Field Day, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 366)
    Negative no.A366. August 18, 1906. Image depicts the bath house and residential buildings viewed from the opposite shore of Hopedale Pond. In the background, in front of the bath house, men in two canoes are pulling on each end of a rope, attempting to gain control in a tug-of-war. Several groups of people are watching from rowboats and canoes nearby. Note the boat in the left background, which seems to consist entirely of women. Spectators can also be seen in front of the bath house and on the shore on either side of the bath house. See also Negative 367 and Negative 369, in this box, for nearly identical shots. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 366 for print of this negative.
  - Canoe Tug-of-War, Field Day, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 367)
    Negative no.A367. August 18, 1906. Image depicts the bath house and residential buildings viewed from the opposite shore of Hopedale Pond. In the background, in front of the bath house, men in two canoes are pulling on each end of a rope, attempting to gain control in a tug-of-war. Several groups of people are watching from rowboats and a canoe nearby. Spectators can also be seen in front of the bath house and on the shore on either side of the bath house. See also Negative 366 and Negative 369, in this box, for nearly identical shots. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 367 for print of this negative.
  - Bath House, Field Day, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 368)
    Negative no.A368. August 18, 1906. Image depicts the bath house and residential buildings viewed from the opposite shore of Hopedale Pond. Several groups of people are rowing canoes and rowboats on the water while some are relaxing on the shore by the bath house. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 368 for print of this negative.
  - Canoe Tug-of-War, Field Day, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 369)
    Negative no.A369. August 18, 1906. Image depicts the bath house and residential buildings viewed from the opposite shore of Hopedale Pond. Men in two canoes are pulling on each end of a rope, attempting to gain control. Several groups of people are watching from rowboats and canoes nearby. See also Negative 366 and Negative 367, in this box, for nearly identical shots. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 369 for print of this negative.
  - Canoe Race Finish, Field Day, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 370)
    Negative no.A370. August 18, 1906. Image depicts the bath house and residential buildings viewed from the opposite shore of Hopedale Pond. Two men in a canoe are visible, possibly the winners of the canoe race? Several groups of people are watching from the shore and rowboats nearby. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 370 for print of this negative.
  - Greased Pole contest, Field Day, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 371)
    Negative no.A371. August 18, 1906. Image depicts a man attempting to walk across a greased pole extending over the water, hoping to avoid slipping and falling into the water (another man is already in the water nearby). Spectators are on the shore and in canoes nearby. In the background is a view of residential buildings on the opposite shore. See also Negative 372 and Negative 373, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 3, Folder 2, Item 371 for print of this negative.
  - Greased Pole contest, Field Day, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 372)